NIKUNJ JADHAV

nikunjjadhav786@gmail.com | +91 7977064992 | linktree/Nixk07 | linkedin/nikunj-jadhav

Profile

A skilled DevOps engineer with 2 years of hands-on experience in enterprise-level IT Infrastructure Design, Continuous Integration, and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) on various cloud providers.

Skills Certification

Programming Languages: C++, Java, Python, Bash

Databases: MySQL, SQL Services (SSIS, SSRS), phpMyAdmin

Version Control: Git. BitBucket

Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Yii2, Flask Python Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib

Cloud Providers: AWS, Azure, GCP

Containerization (Docker) Project management tool: JIRA Data Visualization Tableau, Power-BI Pytorch-Deep learning | Dphi Data Analysis with Python | Dphi **Azure Fundamental**

Credly Porfolio

PubSub+ Cloud:

Solace Certified Developer practitioner, Solace Certified EDA-practitioner, Solace Certified solutions consultant

Work Experience

DevOps Engineer April 2024 - Current

IESoft Technologies, Mumbai

Cloud Associate April 2022 - September 2023

SaphhireInfoTech Ventures Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai

- Worked as a Cloud Associate, creating daily reports in Excel & handling client mail & processing requests.
- Setting up application servers based on various requirements on the cloud while doing on-prem to cloud migration.
- Also helped create disaster recovery plans for various clients for an efficient system operational recovery to their DR site during a catastrophic app failure.
- Technologies: Azure, VM, Storage, S2S & more, AWS services include EC2, S3, Cloudwatch, VPC, Lambda, IAM, etc.

Software Intern February 2022 - April 2022

Synergy Technology, Mumbai

- Built CRUD app with Admin Login, phpMyAdmin Database & Flask used with Foreign Key Tables for Music Webpage.
- From scratch, I built the **plugin** & added ease of use to the users & it's integrated within **WordPress**.
- Technologies: HTML, Javascript, WordPress, PHPMyAdmin, PHP 7, Yii2, Flask.

Web-Development Intern

February 2019 - March 2019

Sahu Technologies, Mumbai

- Designed **Dynamic UI pages**, for Hotel management systems and "Library Management Systems."
- Created a multi-page interactive website, linked it to a database, and deployed it using "PHPMyAdmin."
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHPMyAdmin.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (BSc-IT), Mumbai University CGPA: 7.83/10 2019 - 2021

Diploma in Computer Science, Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education (MSBTE)

2016 - 2019

Projects

Yoga Plus - IIT Bombay's EdTech Hackathon

- Developed an Android app & web app in Flutter that assists users in performing yoga and workouts by using machine learning models in **TensorFlow Lite** and user's stats were stored in **Firebase**.
- The web app uses the webcam to capture images and infers poses using the MAX deep learning model
- Technologies: HTML, CSS3, Javascript, Tensorflow.js, PoseNet, Model Asset Exchange

SOS-Android App

- Developed an Android app that triggers SOS via handset buttons without touching the phone screen
- It uses **voice recognition** to send an **SMS** when a certain word is spoken & then sends live location via SMS.
- Technologies: Java, Android Studio, XML, JDBC, and MS-SQL

Achievements Volunteering

Stood 7th in the IIT Bombay EdTech Hackathon Stood 3rd in the Apscript Hackathon Selected in CII - Debate Competition, State-Wise Youth Volunteer at HariPrabodham [2017-Present]